hey guys welcome to another video in this video we are going to discuss about the one of
the important topic and privilege escalation the access token so many of them not have
an idea about what is an access token in windows probably because the Linux will handle
tokens in a different way so we are not going to discuss that but in windows there is
a concept called as an access token okay so this access token mainly used for a privilege
escalation escalating from on privilege to another another another privilege there was
a main goal we have to do this access token topic let us do a little bit explanation
of access token okay so when you give a username and password and when you try to login
into the machine absolutely the your tromcial username and password get verified instead
of database so whether it was a right username and password or not so once it get
very fed and the username and password also correct the windows operating system will allocate
a certain token okay for you okay that's called as an access token the access token contain
a set of information so you are going to use that token to create a new process or create
a new thread because this access token contains certain information like what's your privilege
for which user group you belongs to and what are the things you can access in windows operating
system example you can't able to enter into see directory if you are a user normal user
you are on your you can't able to open this process there are certain access controls for
you so all the things will be it's a container all the things will be put inside the access
token and the windows operating system will be giving you that so once you got an access
token so after you logged in you can create a new process you can create a new thread
okay so this is the information basically the access token contain the SAD of a user account
so SAD is nothing but so if you you are for my slash all command you can see a unique
SAD that has been allocated for you okay so this SAD the access token contain this
SAD information okay so which and which group belongs to the SAD belongs to which group
it's a user group or an RDP group or any other VPN if there is any other groups inside
the company organization so which group it belongs to and logon sections the main thing
we need to discuss is the default DSS data access control so it will be like a secure
object basically which folder you can access for which files you have a read only permission
write only permission or you have an executable permission so basically the access token
contains this much of information okay so the SAD of it's it's used for a security context
okay because the access token contains a privilege of an user account so which privilege
you have so you can able to access this process or you can able to create the process
or not so this will be completely deserted by the windows access token okay so your windows
mission operating system will provide that so in access token we have two types so one
is a primary token and another one is a impersonate token we'll discuss that token in a different
video the next video but let's say I was in the mission so if I opened the command
program here so now you can see there's a command problem let me open the process hacker
and check the token information so now you can now you can see I just opened a command
prompt not in a administrator mode it's a user privilege which is how you can verify that
so I only have a medium mandatory level of privilege I do not have a high mandatory level but
you can see a privilege information I have only this much of privilege but let me open
the command prompt in a administrator console okay now I will be let me check which promises
which I have open 4804 or so Pd of the CMD so this is the first command CMD I open let's
Wcon this one so now you can find the difference between both of the access this is the
normal privilege and this is the administrator level privilege right and here you can find
a lot of privilege we have also we have a SC impersonate privilege okay impersonate a
client after authentication so we are going to use this API to use this privilege okay
to bypass the access token manipulation attack okay so but the normal user privilege does
not have this SC impersonate privilege so we are we can't able to do the access token
manipulation attack in a normal user privilege okay medium mandatory level so we can only use
token manipulation attack you know administrator mode privilege okay because so here you
can find a SC impersonate level okay so we can impersonate a client after an authentication
it's an enabled okay so in this privilege escalation techniques we are going to develop
a program to do access token manipulation attack we will do we will do it in another video
about a high register something let me open a Cal.exe from administrator level privilege
so now so I already discussed okay so if you need to create any process so your access
token will be used okay so windows will create a process through using your access token so
now if I open a command prompt in administrator mode I have a certain access token for an
administrator so if this administrator open a Cal so now this calculator also have a similar
token okay so if one process burning I mean the way if if CMD.exe triggering Cal.exe
the Cal.exe has the same access token what the administrator command prompt has okay so in
our scenario I just opened the Cal.exe in administrator command prompt so now this administrator
has on access token the same access token will be represented in the Cal.exe in the calculator
okay so let me close this and let me go move to a normal CMD and if I open the CMD Cal.exe
here now this is the normal user privilege this user has a certain access token so sometime
he was unable to access all the files all the resources in here the machine because he is
a medium mandatory level he only has a medium level permission so you can verify so here you
can see medium mandatory level so sometime this user was unable to access many resource in
the machine if I open a Cal.exe inside from this command CMD.exe so this Cal.exe contains
the access token for a normal C command prompt okay so let's repeat one more time so if any of
the higher privilege process spend or triggered and another process so the target process so
the triggering process that has an access token of the process food triggered maybe in our
scenario it's a command.exe that spun this Cal.exe okay so if the CMD.exe has a lesser
privilege access token so the triggering process will also have a lesser privilege okay if the
CMD has a higher level of privilege the triggering process will also have a higher privilege
of access token okay so that's a scenario here so we'll discuss about the types of access token
in our upcoming video so let's hop off and we'll see you guys in the next video bye bye